<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quotes on Personal Website of Tom Lianza</title>
    <link>https://lianza.org/quotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quotes on Personal Website of Tom Lianza</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 06:28:47 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://lianza.org/quotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Facts</title>
      <link>https://lianza.org/quotes/facts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 06:28:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lianza.org/quotes/facts/</guid>
      <description>Celebrities&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; Animals&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; Cultures&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; People&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; Words&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; Food&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; Random  This is an extremely long page, and is designed as such to be easily printable. You can jump to any of the sections via the hyperlinks at the top.
Movies/TV/Celebrity Stuff  The characters Bert and Ernie on Sesame Street were named after Bert the cop and Ernie the taxi driver in Frank Capra&#39;s &amp;quot;Its A Wonderful Life&amp;quot; All of the clocks in the movie Pulp Fiction are stuck on 4:20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Excerpts</title>
      <link>https://lianza.org/quotes/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lianza.org/quotes/books/</guid>
      <description>The Geneology of Morals&#34;Nietzsche&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; The Stranger&#34;Camus&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; Hadith&#34;Muhammed&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; The Unbearable Lightness of Being&#34;Kundera&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; Religion is a Gigantic Fraud&#34;Johnson  From Nietzsche&#39;s Genealogy of Morals When the oppressed, downtrodden, outraged exhort one another with the vengeful cunning of impotence: &amp;quot;let us be different from the evil, namely good! And he is good who does not outrage, who harms nobody, who does not attack, who does not requite, who leaves revenge to God, who keeps himself hidden as we do, who avoids evil and desires little from life, like us, the patient, humble, and just&amp;quot; --this, listened to calmly and without previous bias, really amounts to no more than: &amp;quot;we weak ones are, after all, weak; it would be good if we did nothing for which we are not strong enough&amp;quot;; but this dry matter of fact, this prudence of the lowest order which even insects posess (posing as dead, when in great danger, so as not to do &amp;quot;too much&amp;quot;), has, thanks to the counterfeit and self-deception of impotence, clad itself in the ostentatious garb of the virtue of quiet, calm resignation, just as if the weakness of the weak--that is to say, their essence, their effects, their sole ineluctable, irremovable reality--were a voluntary achievement, willed, chosen, a deed, a meritorious act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funny Quotes</title>
      <link>https://lianza.org/quotes/funny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lianza.org/quotes/funny/</guid>
      <description>Definitions&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; I Wonder&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; Wise Words&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; One-Liners&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; Laws&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; Last Words&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; by Author&amp;nbsp;|&amp;nbsp; Random  This is an extremely long page, and is designed as such to be easily printable. You can jump to any of the sections via the hyperlinks at the top. Definitions  Antonym - The opposite of the word you&#39;re trying to think of. Bore - A person with nothing to say and says it. Diplomacy - letting them have it your way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>